<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Technology | Gotchacode]]></title>
  <link href="http://gotchacode.com/blog/categories/technology/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gotchacode.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-15T08:12:31+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://gotchacode.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinit Kumar]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinitcool76@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google+ Gets New Look and Cool Features.]]></title>
    <link href="http://gotchacode.com/2011/12/google-gets-new-look-and-cool-features.html"/>
    <updated>2011-12-01T12:02:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gotchacode.com/2011/12/google-gets-new-look-and-cool-features</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="css-full-post-content js-full-post-content">
There is one thing that is very noticeable about Google+ and that is the way it is evolving. When it first came in it had nothing very special so as to take Social Networking giant Facebook . But recently some very cool and clean looking features has been incorporated into Google+.<br/><br/>In the first screenshot you can see that there is a new navigation UI in Google+, just click the Google+ logo and you will get all the options such a profile page, Search, Images, Maps, Youtube, News, Gmail,Documents etc.<br/><br/>It might prove a very decisive move from Google+ to incorporate all the existing services that are being used by millions into Social Networking realm.The switch seems perfectly clean and everything works like wonders.<br/><br/>[caption id="attachment_568" align="alignleft" width="580" caption="New Way To Navigate in Google+"]<a href="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/pic.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-568" title="pic" src="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/pic.png" alt="" width="580" height="326" /></a>[/caption]<br/><br/>Also in the next one we can see that a very portable YouTube player incorporated in the right, Just search in your favorite artist/band and it will be lined up in a convenient playlist. So you can actually use the Netflix kind of services for free and in many cases more better.<br/><br/>[caption id="attachment_571" align="alignleft" width="580" caption="YouTube Videos In A Cool Playlist Mode."]<a href="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/screenshot7.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-571" title="screenshot7" src="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/screenshot7.png" alt="" width="580" height="326" /></a>[/caption]<br/><br/>This is the latest addition in Google+, a brand new share button so that you can update your status, add pics or whatever you wish even if u are using any of the Google services like gmail.<br/><br/>[caption id="attachment_572" align="alignleft" width="580" caption="New Share Button On The Top Sidebar Of Gmail and Google+"]<a href="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/pic3.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-572" title="pic3" src="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/pic3.png" alt="" width="580" height="326" /></a>[/caption]<br/><br/>&nbsp;<br/><br/>So Looking at the new features we can definitely predict that future seems bright for Google+ and though the growth is slow, it might be a steady and long lasting one.
</div>


<div class="css-full-comments-content js-full-comments-content">
<div class="css-full-comment js-full-comment">
  <div class="css-comment-user-link js-comment-user-link">
  <a href="http://www.tomatosoft.biz/blog/2011/12/03/new-ui-of-youtube/">
  <div class="css-comment-name js-comment-name">
    Tomato Blog
  </div>
  </a>
  <div class="css-comment-date js-comment-date">
    2011-12-04T00:51:06.000Z
  </div>
  </div>
  <div class="css-comment-content js-comment-content">
    <strong>New UI of youtube...</strong><br><br>Youtube has updated to a new design of UI, along with other products of google like: adsense, analytics, webmaster tools, gmail. The most significant change is the background, it’s no longer white, replaced with a texture based background image, ...
  </div>
  <br/>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iPad 2 Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://gotchacode.com/2011/03/ipad-2-review.html"/>
    <updated>2011-03-04T10:35:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gotchacode.com/2011/03/ipad-2-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="css-full-post-content js-full-post-content">
<strong><strong><a title="iPad 2 : Thinner, Lighter and  Faster!  " href="http://gotchacode.wordpress.com/2011/03/04/ipad-2-launched/">iPad 2 : Thinner, Lighter and  <strong>Faster</strong>!</a></strong></strong><br/><br/>Amit Kr<br/><p style="text-align:justify;"><strong> </strong></p><br/><strong><a href="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/ipad_front_201103021.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-523 aligncenter" title="ipad_front_20110302" src="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/ipad_front_201103021.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="252" /></a></strong><br/><p style="text-align:center;">The new iPad2 ©</p><br/><strong>Now </strong>that the new iPad 2 has finally been announced; many of you might have been wondering if it is worth the efforts (read long queues) and the money to buy a new iPad 2. Well, I think the answer is a resounding Yes!! Apple has come with some innovative new features and great upgrades in iPad 2.  Here we preview some of the features of iPad 2 and also compare it with iPad so it is easy for our readers to decide if iPad 2 is worth the upgrade.<br/><br/>iPad 2 comes with a <strong>long list of features</strong>.  The first thing that got us excited in iPad 2 is the smart cover. There's a new cover for the device, which is best defined by Steve Jobs himself: "We designed the case right alongside the product. It's not a case -- it's a cover." Basically, it's a magnetic flap that protects the front and automatically wakes and puts the device to sleep according to whether it's open or closed. It takes only milliseconds to open and close the cover and the whole process is flawless.<br/><br/>The new iPad 2 is 15% lighter than iPad and at 613 grams , it feels very comfortable to hold in hands.  It is also 33% thinner than the original iPad and at just 8.8 mm, you really forget the device and get immersed in the Apple feeling.<br/><br/>You must have heard that external looks are not everything. It is what inside the heart that counts. Apple does not disappoint us at that too. With the new A5 Dual Core processor; the new iPad2 is claimed by Apple to be twice as fast and the graphics performance is up to nine times better than on the original iPad, while power requirements have been kept the same. Battery life is great with Apple promising 10 hours. That means you can keep yourself hooked to movies on that trans-Atlantic flight without worrying about recharge.<br/><br/>One of the great things about iPad 2 is the dual cameras : Front and rear cameras.  The front camera is a VGA camera that can be used for facetime chats with other iPad, iPhone, iPod, and Mac users.  The rear camera can shoot 720p HD video at 30 fps.<br/><br/>The new iPad will come with the newest version of Apple’s mobile operating system iOS 4.3.  This update enables better performance while using the Safari Internet browser, iTunes home sharing and Airplay improvements. It will also include the Wi-Fi hotspot capabilities found in the Verizon iPhones.<br/><br/>With built in gyroscope, high end processors and new apps for iMovie and GarageBand; the iPad 2 is a great multimedia experience.<br/><br/><strong>Pricing :</strong><br/><br/><strong>AT&amp;T introduced </strong><a href="http://www.att.com/gen/press-room?pid=19258&amp;cdvn=news&amp;newsarticleid=31658&amp;mapcode=broadband|consumer">two new postpaid plans for tablets</a>, a category that includes the <a href="http://www.tuaw.com/2011/03/02/apple-announces-ipad-2-in-2-colors-will-feature-dual-cameras-an/">upcoming iPad 2</a>. Unlike prepaid plans which require customers to buy data allotments upfront, these new plans can be added to a customer's current monthly cellular bill. This new postpaid option is month-to-month and does not require a long-term commitment.<br/><br/>Pricing for the postpaid plans mirror the prepaid plans with a $14.99 plan that provides 250 MB of data or a $25 plan with 2 GB of data. Overages on the new postpaid plans will be charged at a rate of $10 per 1 GB of overage. This is slightly less than the prepaid plans which charge customers $25 for an additional 2 GB of usage. These new plans give customers the freedom to choose how they would like to be billed for data to be used with their shiny new 3G iPad 2.<br/><br/>As a benefit for <a href="http://www.tuaw.com/2011/03/03/will-you-buy-an-ipad-2/">early adopters</a> of the iPad 2, AT&amp;T is offering a limited-time promotion that provides one free month of service for those that signup for the new $25/2 GB plan.<br/><br/>Below we have given a comparison table of iPad vs iPad 2.<br/><div><br/><table border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="5" width="475" align="center"><br/><tbody><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" align="center" valign="top"><strong>iPad</strong></td><br/><td width="170" align="center" valign="top"><strong>iPad 2</strong></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" align="center" valign="top"><img src="http://timenerdworld.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/ipadsm.jpg?w=488" alt="" /></td><br/><td width="170" align="center" valign="top"><img src="http://timenerdworld.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/ipad2sm.jpg?w=488" alt="" /></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Base Price</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top"><a href="http://store.apple.com/us/product/FB292LL/A?mco=MjEzNTI3MDQ">$349</a> (refurb), <a href="http://store.apple.com/us/product/MB292LL/A?mco=MjEzNzE1ODc">$399</a>(new)</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top"><a href="http://www.apple.com/ipad/">$499</a></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="170" valign="top"></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Colors</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top">Black</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top">Black or White</td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="170" valign="top"></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Dimensions</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top">9.56 x 7.47 x 0.5 inches</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top">9.5 x 7.31 x 0.34 inches</td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Weight</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top">1.5-1.6 pounds</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top">1.33-1.35 pounds</td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="170" valign="top"></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Storage</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top">16GB/32GB/64GB</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top">16GB/32GB/64GB</td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="170" valign="top"></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Connections</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top">Wi-Fi, Bluetooth, optional AT&amp;T 3G</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top">Wi-Fi, Bluetooth, optional AT&amp;T 3G or Verizon 3G</td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="170" valign="top"></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Screen</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top">9.7-inch 1024x768</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top">9.7-inch 1024x768</td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="170" valign="top"></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Processor</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top">1GHz A4</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top">1GHz dual-core A5</td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="170" valign="top"></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Battery</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top">Up to 10 hours</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top">Up to 10 hours</td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="170" valign="top"></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Cameras</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top">None</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top">720p rear, VGA front</td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="170" valign="top"></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Sensors</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top">Accelerometer, Ambient light sensor</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top">Accelerometer, Ambient light sensor, 3-axis gyro</td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="170" valign="top"></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Location</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top">Wi-Fi, Compass, Optional GPS (3G version)</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top">Wi-Fi, Compass, Optional GPS (3G versions)</td><br/></tr><br/></tbody><br/></table><br/></div><br/><div><strong>Conclusion </strong>:</div><br/><div>With the great list of features and the magical Apple feeling found in every Apple device; I think iPad 2 is a great buy for new user and iPad users alike.  It will be available in stores and online from March 11.</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress Toward terabit-Rate High Density Recording]]></title>
    <link href="http://gotchacode.com/2010/10/progress-toward-terabit-rate-high.html"/>
    <updated>2010-10-15T07:52:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gotchacode.com/2010/10/progress-toward-terabit-rate-high</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="css-full-post-content js-full-post-content">
<h2>Research is closing in on the next-generation of ultra-high-density magneto-optical storage devices that could store more than 6,000 Terabits (6 petabits) of data, more than 70 times the contents of the entire U.S. Library of Congress, on a single 5-inch disc.</h2><br/>Yet the vast storage amount is limited by the ability to write data quickly enough to the device. In the Journal of Applied Physics, researchers at Sun Yat-Sen University in China have demonstrated a way to record on ferromagnetic films using a laser-assisted ultrafast magnetization reversal dynamics.<br/><br/>The technique uses so-called time-resolved polar Kerr spectroscopy combined with an alternating magnetic field strong enough to re-initialize the magnetization state of gadolinium-iron-cobalt (GdFeCo) thin films. Tianshu Lai and colleagues showed that the magnetization reversal could occur in a sub-nanosecond time scale, which implies that next- generation magneto-optical storage devices can not only realize higher recording densities but also ultrafast data writing of up to a gigahertz. Such speed is at least thirty times faster than that of present hard disks in computers.<br/><br/>Laser-assisted magnetic recording was demonstrated on a sub-picosecond time scale under a saturated external magnetic field. "We found that the rate of magnetization reversal is proportional to the external magnetic field," says Lai, "and the genuine thermo-magnetic recording should happen within several tens to hundreds of picoseconds when we apply a smaller magnetic field than the coercivity of the recording films."
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nokia Touchscreen Creates Texture Illusion]]></title>
    <link href="http://gotchacode.com/2010/10/nokia-touchscreen-creates-texture.html"/>
    <updated>2010-10-10T16:01:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gotchacode.com/2010/10/nokia-touchscreen-creates-texture</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="css-full-post-content js-full-post-content">
<a href="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2010/10/nokia-n900_003.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-372" title="nokia-n900_003" src="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2010/10/nokia-n900_003.jpg" alt="" width="497" height="390" /></a><br/><br/><strong>Nokia has developed a prototype of its N900 smartphone that lets you feel the texture of icons on the screen</strong><br/><br/>A technology that would add a whole new dimension to touchscreen apps. This week, Nokia researcher Piers Andrew showed how the technology could give each icon its own feel or add surface texture to photographs. "The idea is to have everything on a touchscreen give tactile feedback," Andrew says. The technology is based on an effect called electrovibration, in which touch receptors in the skin can be fooled into perceiving texture when you swipe a fingertip across an insulating layer above a metal surface carrying an alternating voltage. The higher the frequency of that alternating voltage, the smoother the texture feels. "It's an effect that's been known about since the 1950s," says Andrew. Often when electrical equipment was poorly earthed, people could feel a mysterious rough surface as they swept a fingertip across a visibly smooth, insulator-coated metal surface carrying a varying voltage (Science, DOI: 10.1126/science.118.3062.277).<br/><br/><a href="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2010/10/nokia-n900_001.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-371" title="nokia-n900_001" src="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2010/10/nokia-n900_001.jpg" alt="" width="326" height="550" /></a><br/><br/><em><strong>Rough to the touch </strong></em><br/><br/>The effect is thought to be due to the varying electrostatic attraction between the metal and the deeper, liquid-rich conducting layers of the skin – an effect which changes the perceived friction level. To mimic this is in a touchscreen phone, Nokia placed two thin layers above the LCD display: the first a transparent conductor, indium tin oxide, and the second a transparent insulator, hafnium oxide. When the user cradles the phone in one hand and touches the screen with the fingers of their other hand, they effectively create a closed circuit. If the indium tin oxide is excited at frequencies between 50 and 200 hertz, the finger above the touchscreen is attracted towards the screen with varying strength, generating the textured effect. You will only feel texture if you move the finger across the surface, and since the prototype can generate just one frequency at a time, only one on-screen texture can be felt at any moment. To enable multitouch – with different fingers simultaneously experiencing different textures on the display – Nokia will have to modify the system to apply different frequencies to different areas of the screen. Nokia has filed a patent on its ideas, but Andrew admits the concept still needs some work. "This is not necessarily the most attractive sensation for some people," he says.<br/><br/><em><strong>Singular sensation </strong></em><br/><br/>Ian Summers at the University of Exeter, UK, agrees. "Electrotactile stimulation has a long history. The problem has always been to control the sensation as skin conductivity changes from minute to minute and from person to person." The cellphone manufacturer is not alone in its pursuit of texture for touchscreens. Academic groups around the world are exploring similar ideas, and Toshiba is also developing electrostatic displays in collaboration with Finnish start-up Senseg of Helsinki. When will Nokia launch this phone? "This interface is still very much in the research phase. The ultimate goal is to integrate the research into future Nokia devices – but it's too early to say when," says Frederique Slezak, a Nokia spokeswoman. Yon Visell, a specialist in tactile interfaces at McGill University in Montreal, Canada, looks forward to such capability: "Tactile feedback is the most glaringly omitted dimension in touchscreen devices like the Apple iPhone or iPad. The device can feel what we're touching, but we can't," he says.
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
