<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: JavaScript | My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://gotchacode.github.io/blog/categories/javascript/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gotchacode.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-14T11:32:25+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://gotchacode.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[JavaScript Is an Adult , See What It Can Do Now.]]></title>
    <link href="http://gotchacode.github.io/2013/06/javascript-is-adult-now-see-what-it-can.html"/>
    <updated>2013-06-01T18:48:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gotchacode.github.io/2013/06/javascript-is-adult-now-see-what-it-can</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="css-full-post-content js-full-post-content">
<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><object class="BLOGGER-youtube-video" classid="clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0" data-thumbnail-src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/qrf9ONmtXbM/0.jpg" height="266" width="320"><param name="movie" value="http://youtube.googleapis.com/v/qrf9ONmtXbM&source=uds" /><param name="bgcolor" value="#FFFFFF" /><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><embed width="320" height="266"  src="http://youtube.googleapis.com/v/qrf9ONmtXbM&source=uds" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object></div>The first version of JS was released in 10 days. Enjoy this talk by it's founder. Enjoy it with some good coffee.<br /><br /></div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Setup a Mac for Web Development.]]></title>
    <link href="http://gotchacode.github.io/2013/02/how-to-setup-mac-for-web-development.html"/>
    <updated>2013-02-24T17:56:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gotchacode.github.io/2013/02/how-to-setup-mac-for-web-development</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="css-full-post-content js-full-post-content">
<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on">Macs are beautiful machine. Luckily, I own a Macbook Pro that has 8GB ram and 256GB SSD. I am a Web Developer by profession so here are some tips that you could use to setup your mac.<br /><br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-UGabibWAlr8/USpTz8VpRUI/AAAAAAAABBk/ry2cD5pt7eM/s1600/Screen+Shot+2013-02-24+at+11.22.59+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="250" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-UGabibWAlr8/USpTz8VpRUI/AAAAAAAABBk/ry2cD5pt7eM/s400/Screen+Shot+2013-02-24+at+11.22.59+PM.png" width="400" /></a></div><ul style="text-align: left;"><li>Install Xcode: Install Xcode,&nbsp;preferably&nbsp;the full version, if you might like to develop for iOS or iPad. It is a free download from App Store.</li><li>Install Homebrew: This is a must and it is really satisfies the need to package manager in OSX.</li><li>Install dotfiles: Please use dotfiles, there are many good ones already shared on Github. You can use any one of them from here. <a href="http://dotfiles.github.com/" target="_blank">Install Dotfiles</a></li><li>Install z, oh-my-zsh: Oh my zsh is one of the best and feature rich shell, do use it with combination of z. Z is a directory jumping tool and it is really handy. <a href="https://github.com/rupa/z" target="_blank">Install Z</a></li><li>Install and configure a text editor: Install Sublime Text2, Vim or Emacs as your text editor. They are most extensible and powerful editors and you can configure them to satisfy all your needs. Make sure you invest sometime configuring it to your taste and needs. It will be intensely productive and satisfying experience.</li><li>Install Node and NPM: If you are web developer , you must have dealt with JavaScript. You must install both of them. Not only it extends the package manager needs, it is basis of other good package managers for web.</li><li>Install Component, Yeoman, Bower and Grunt. These are some&nbsp;indispensable&nbsp;tools that are very important for any web /&nbsp;web app&nbsp;developer.</li><li>Install Chrome Canary: If you want to get the best Developer tools available , install chrome canary. It is the latest and provide great support for various things such as sass, compass etc inbuilt.</li><li>Install Google drive and dropbox: Please keep your important stuff in cloud so that you may never loose your data again. Also, you can backup your code in Github.</li><li>Install SizeUP: It is one of most productive software on mac and provides such great arrangement of Windows that you will be amazed. Either buy it or install the trial version.&nbsp;<a href="http://www.irradiatedsoftware.com/" target="_blank">Install Sizeup</a></li><li>Install Git and create a account on Github, if you haven't already. There is such a vibrant community on Github, mostly great web developers that if you are not updated with it.You will loose great deal of useful information.</li><li>Automate most of the grunt jobs you do daily. Use build tools such as Make, Cake, Jake etc. Also, learn little bit of shell scripting. It really helps in long run.</li><li>Install Python and the module install tools such a pip and easy_install. It is really a must.</li><li>Install Ruby and ROR. They have pretty good community. Just a basis google search will get you going about the install and use process.</li><li>Install VirtualBox, it is an invaluable thing if you have to use another OS such as Windows or Ubuntu.</li></ul><div>I guess these are pretty exhaustive list of TODOS if you using mac for web/web-app development. I will keep updating the post if i remember any more important thing. The baseline is that macs are great piece of hardware and a pretty decent OS, so invest sometime in setting it up. It will save you tons of time and frustation. Have a good weekend, Enjoy!</div></div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Github Watch: Languages]]></title>
    <link href="http://gotchacode.github.io/2012/09/github-watch-languages.html"/>
    <updated>2012-09-02T05:01:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gotchacode.github.io/2012/09/github-watch-languages</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="css-full-post-content js-full-post-content">
<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div style="text-align: justify;">Github is easily the world's largest repository for projects with almost all major companies as well as Startups &nbsp;use them to deploy their code or contribute to Open Source.&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">This is a small infographic of Top 10 Languages that are used to create projects at Github.</div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-HJeXwmNDfoo/UELkbL4YMHI/AAAAAAAAA1k/x6851ZQ7k_0/s1600/screen5.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="195" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-HJeXwmNDfoo/UELkbL4YMHI/AAAAAAAAA1k/x6851ZQ7k_0/s400/screen5.png" width="400" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;I will try to analyze what we can deduce from this data.&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">JavaScript, Ruby and Python take first three places. It was quite obvious because Developers are more focused to develop stuff for web and these languages provide everything you need to create a great looking website or App that can scale. Node , Rails and Django are the most famous projects that are trending nowadays.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">One shocker is Shell Beating Java and PHP, well all we can make out from this data is that most of people or a huge percentage using Github are *nix users (either OS X or Linux ) . One factor can also be that people might not want to Open Source there java projects or PHP ones.Its a highly competitive market and sure we can't blame them.&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">Next up we have C, C++ , Perl and Objective-C. It was obvious because C and C++ are tougher to learn compared to languages such as python, Ruby or JavaScript.Objective-C in the list shows that iOS developers are also contributing to Open Source projects at Github.</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">This data might not be accurate to the developers language choice and Projects, but surely gives us a view of what current trend is.</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div></div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
