<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Sublime Text | Gotchacode]]></title>
  <link href="http://gotchacode.github.io/blog/categories/sublime-text/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gotchacode.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-14T12:52:28+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://gotchacode.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinit Kumar]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinitcool76@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Setup a Mac for Web Development.]]></title>
    <link href="http://gotchacode.github.io/2013/02/how-to-setup-mac-for-web-development.html"/>
    <updated>2013-02-24T17:56:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gotchacode.github.io/2013/02/how-to-setup-mac-for-web-development</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="css-full-post-content js-full-post-content">
<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on">Macs are beautiful machine. Luckily, I own a Macbook Pro that has 8GB ram and 256GB SSD. I am a Web Developer by profession so here are some tips that you could use to setup your mac.<br /><br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-UGabibWAlr8/USpTz8VpRUI/AAAAAAAABBk/ry2cD5pt7eM/s1600/Screen+Shot+2013-02-24+at+11.22.59+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="250" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-UGabibWAlr8/USpTz8VpRUI/AAAAAAAABBk/ry2cD5pt7eM/s400/Screen+Shot+2013-02-24+at+11.22.59+PM.png" width="400" /></a></div><ul style="text-align: left;"><li>Install Xcode: Install Xcode,&nbsp;preferably&nbsp;the full version, if you might like to develop for iOS or iPad. It is a free download from App Store.</li><li>Install Homebrew: This is a must and it is really satisfies the need to package manager in OSX.</li><li>Install dotfiles: Please use dotfiles, there are many good ones already shared on Github. You can use any one of them from here. <a href="http://dotfiles.github.com/" target="_blank">Install Dotfiles</a></li><li>Install z, oh-my-zsh: Oh my zsh is one of the best and feature rich shell, do use it with combination of z. Z is a directory jumping tool and it is really handy. <a href="https://github.com/rupa/z" target="_blank">Install Z</a></li><li>Install and configure a text editor: Install Sublime Text2, Vim or Emacs as your text editor. They are most extensible and powerful editors and you can configure them to satisfy all your needs. Make sure you invest sometime configuring it to your taste and needs. It will be intensely productive and satisfying experience.</li><li>Install Node and NPM: If you are web developer , you must have dealt with JavaScript. You must install both of them. Not only it extends the package manager needs, it is basis of other good package managers for web.</li><li>Install Component, Yeoman, Bower and Grunt. These are some&nbsp;indispensable&nbsp;tools that are very important for any web /&nbsp;web app&nbsp;developer.</li><li>Install Chrome Canary: If you want to get the best Developer tools available , install chrome canary. It is the latest and provide great support for various things such as sass, compass etc inbuilt.</li><li>Install Google drive and dropbox: Please keep your important stuff in cloud so that you may never loose your data again. Also, you can backup your code in Github.</li><li>Install SizeUP: It is one of most productive software on mac and provides such great arrangement of Windows that you will be amazed. Either buy it or install the trial version.&nbsp;<a href="http://www.irradiatedsoftware.com/" target="_blank">Install Sizeup</a></li><li>Install Git and create a account on Github, if you haven't already. There is such a vibrant community on Github, mostly great web developers that if you are not updated with it.You will loose great deal of useful information.</li><li>Automate most of the grunt jobs you do daily. Use build tools such as Make, Cake, Jake etc. Also, learn little bit of shell scripting. It really helps in long run.</li><li>Install Python and the module install tools such a pip and easy_install. It is really a must.</li><li>Install Ruby and ROR. They have pretty good community. Just a basis google search will get you going about the install and use process.</li><li>Install VirtualBox, it is an invaluable thing if you have to use another OS such as Windows or Ubuntu.</li></ul><div>I guess these are pretty exhaustive list of TODOS if you using mac for web/web-app development. I will keep updating the post if i remember any more important thing. The baseline is that macs are great piece of hardware and a pretty decent OS, so invest sometime in setting it up. It will save you tons of time and frustation. Have a good weekend, Enjoy!</div></div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Configure Sublime Text2 for JavaScript Development.]]></title>
    <link href="http://gotchacode.github.io/2013/02/configure-sublime-text2-for-javascript.html"/>
    <updated>2013-02-24T11:19:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gotchacode.github.io/2013/02/configure-sublime-text2-for-javascript</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="css-full-post-content js-full-post-content">
<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on">I recently started using Sublime Text2 full time at work after being a vim user for more than 4 years. Vim is really good but it takes sometime to configure it properly. Well this is not a Vim vs ST2 debate. It is more of a vim user shifting to ST2 Tip.<br /><br />The first thing that you should do is to install package control, it provide really good 3rd party plugins. You can check out the link how to install it.&nbsp;<a href="http://wbond.net/sublime_packages/package_control/installation" target="_blank">Install Package Control</a><br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-VyTJ6GhccRQ/USn4XUWXanI/AAAAAAAABBU/JM261l4WaZw/s1600/Screen+Shot+2013-02-24+at+4.52.12+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="250" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-VyTJ6GhccRQ/USn4XUWXanI/AAAAAAAABBU/JM261l4WaZw/s400/Screen+Shot+2013-02-24+at+4.52.12+PM.png" width="400" /></a></div><br /><br />Once done with that open package manager and install these useful plugins<br /><br /><ul style="text-align: left;"><li>JSHint.</li><li>JSLint.</li><li>DocBlockr.</li><li>AngularJS.</li><li>Mocha &amp; Mocha snippet&nbsp;</li><li>NodeJS.</li><li>Live Reload.</li><li>AMD Module Editor</li><li>Backbone.js</li><li>Pretty JSON</li><li>Require Node.js Module Helper</li></ul><div><br /></div><div>Among, these plugins mocha is the test runner and mocha snippets provides you will snippets to write the tests very fast. Also, there is good plugin for vim mode in Sublime Text2, you can use that if you don't want to waste the muscle memory.&nbsp;I highly recommend the real time linting with JSHint. It will make you so much more&nbsp;productive and improve your code as well. It acts as the first unit test against the code you just wrote.&nbsp;</div><div><br /></div><div>One more important thing, you could set the indentation with tab width equals to 2 spaces. It is a very sane default while writing JavaScript code.</div><div><br /></div><div>What really struck me was that Sublime Text enabled me to do almost everything i did with Vim without going into the pain of configuration. Also, the learning curve is not at all steep so i could get productive real fast.</div></div>
</div>


<div class="css-full-comments-content js-full-comments-content">
<div class="css-full-comment js-full-comment">
  <div class="css-comment-user-link js-comment-user-link">
  <a href="http://www.blogger.com/profile/16586618300856804621">
  <div class="css-comment-name js-comment-name">
    Unknown
  </div>
  </a>
  <div class="css-comment-date js-comment-date">
    2013-02-24T16:08:16.461Z
  </div>
  </div>
  <div class="css-comment-content js-comment-content">
    2013 Wishes: Sublime Text Terminal
  </div>
  <br/>
</div>
<div class="css-full-comment js-full-comment">
  <div class="css-comment-user-link js-comment-user-link">
  <a href="http://www.blogger.com/profile/16586618300856804621">
  <div class="css-comment-name js-comment-name">
    Unknown
  </div>
  </a>
  <div class="css-comment-date js-comment-date">
    2013-02-24T16:08:56.069Z
  </div>
  </div>
  <div class="css-comment-content js-comment-content">
    2013 Wishes: Sublime Text Terminal
  </div>
  <br/>
</div>
<div class="css-full-comment js-full-comment">
  <div class="css-comment-user-link js-comment-user-link">
  <a href="http://www.blogger.com/profile/17194318708068141006">
  <div class="css-comment-name js-comment-name">
    Frank
  </div>
  </a>
  <div class="css-comment-date js-comment-date">
    2013-02-26T22:14:30.778Z
  </div>
  </div>
  <div class="css-comment-content js-comment-content">
    How do you debug javascript using the chrome debugger
  </div>
  <br/>
</div>
<div class="css-full-comment js-full-comment">
  <div class="css-comment-user-link js-comment-user-link">
  <a href="http://www.blogger.com/profile/00121175657676051962">
  <div class="css-comment-name js-comment-name">
    Joel
  </div>
  </a>
  <div class="css-comment-date js-comment-date">
    2013-06-30T01:57:24.119Z
  </div>
  </div>
  <div class="css-comment-content js-comment-content">
    Which mocha plugin are you referring to, the runner? or the snippet package? I&#39;m assuming you mean the runner, but I wasn&#39;t sure at first...and in the interest of clarity for others who may also have this question, perhaps you could clarify?  My experience with the rest of the plugins was smooth, however.
  </div>
  <br/>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
