<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Browsers | Gotchacode]]></title>
  <link href="http://gotchacode.com/blog/categories/browsers/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gotchacode.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-15T07:42:21+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://gotchacode.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinit Kumar]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinitcool76@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tips for Optimizing Chrome Extension]]></title>
    <link href="http://gotchacode.com/2012/12/tips-for-optimizing-chrome-extension.html"/>
    <updated>2012-12-19T07:57:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gotchacode.com/2012/12/tips-for-optimizing-chrome-extension</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="css-full-post-content js-full-post-content">
<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on">Here are some tips for optimizing Google Chrome Extensions:<br /><br />One should check these things at first,<br /><br />Open the Chrome task manager and check CPU and RAM usage for your extension. Also check how this value changes for your extensions after full day of Chrome run. If RAM usage &gt; 15mb it must be a serious reason not to release it without optimizations. Also if CPU value above zero on a persistence basis is bad sign too.<br /><br />Also closure compiler can help your code execute faster. &nbsp;If your have identified that the execution of code is more of an issue than the potential of&nbsp;maximizing&nbsp;the speed of your end points. Also if you are dealing with facebook API , working through bulks calls to Facebook and catching that locally seems to improve performance. Another important thing to note is that if you are concerned with speed or delay tour user experiences, then UI design is a great place to start. The&nbsp;perceived speed of an application can be significantly altered just be settings expectations&nbsp;appropriately, with regard to the speed with which a particular process will execute. So tell users it will take 10 secs when it takes 8 secs.<br /><br />This post is based on a question i asked on Chrome Extension group, you can check out the thread <a href="https://groups.google.com/a/chromium.org/d/topic/chromium-extensions/jNNksFBpa3A/discussion" target="_blank">here</a>. Since these tips are quite handy i thought of sharing them in here in form of a blog post. Hope this helps!<br /><br /><br /></div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 4 Beta- a Complete Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://gotchacode.com/2010/10/firefox-4-beta-complete-review.html"/>
    <updated>2010-10-23T19:15:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gotchacode.com/2010/10/firefox-4-beta-complete-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="css-full-post-content js-full-post-content">
Firefox 4 ,with sync and panorama ,provides a faster and much more personalized browsing experience.<br/><br/><strong> New look</strong><br/><br/>Firefox 4 beta comes in a sleeker and easier to use look with a firefox menu button on top left and new location of tabs.The tabs have been given top visual priority.<br/><br/><strong>SYNC</strong><br/><br/>Found an interesting website just when you were about to leave??Browser is now mobile!Using sync you can access your saved passwords, history ,open tabs and all other customizations using any computer or mobile device that uses firefox.For this you need to create a Firefox Sync account.<br/><br/>For instructions on how to use sync view&nbsp; http://videos.mozilla.org/serv/firefox4beta/syncvideo5final640x3%23161DA3.ogv<br/><br/><strong>PANORAMA</strong><br/><br/><a href="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2010/10/firefox-panorama1.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-417" title="Firefox-Panorama" src="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2010/10/firefox-panorama1.jpg" alt="firefox-panorama" width="144" height="144" /></a><br/><br/>Firefox introduces panorama to organize tabs.You can drag tabs into tabspaces to make groups or piles and then open or expand respectively to navigate through them.Groups can be named, expanded or squeezed and managed quite visually.This helps to keep distractions out of sight for ‘clutter-free’ browsing.<br/><br/>For instructions on how to use panorama view<br/><br/>http://videos.mozilla.org/serv/firefox4beta/grouptabs.theora.ogv<br/><br/><strong>Feedback</strong><br/><br/>Using the Feedback add-on on the upper right corner you can give feedback about the browser any time.<br/><br/>Feedback add-on privacy policy<br/><br/>http://www.mozilla.com/en-US/firefox/beta/feedbackprivacypolicy/<br/><br/><strong>Managing plugins</strong><br/><br/>To ensure uninterrupted browsing ,firefox provides support in case commonly-used plugins Adobe Falsh, Quicktime or Microsoft Silverlight crash or freeze.You can simply reload the page and restart the plugin.<br/><br/><strong>Others</strong><br/><br/>-add-ons can be managed better and can be installed without restarting the browser.<br/><br/>-supports the webM format so that you can watch Hd videos.<br/><br/>-cleaner graphics<br/><br/>-super fast scrolling on complex web pages.<br/><br/><a href="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2010/10/firefox_4_beta.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-413" title="firefox_4_beta" src="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2010/10/firefox_4_beta.jpg" alt="firefox 4 beta" width="510" height="392" /></a><br/><br/><a href="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2010/10/screen-tab-location.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-418" title="screen-tab-location" src="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2010/10/screen-tab-location.png" alt="" width="510" height="132" /></a>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flock Browser….]]></title>
    <link href="http://gotchacode.com/2010/10/flock-browser.html"/>
    <updated>2010-10-20T17:43:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gotchacode.com/2010/10/flock-browser</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="css-full-post-content js-full-post-content">
Flock is the Internet browser targeted towards social butterflies. Flock is the Mozilla powered browser that specifically meets the needs of online social networkers by helping you keep informed when friends post or a favorite site is updated. It has a slick interface and plenty of features.<br/><br/>Flock is equipped to keep you up to date with your contacts from Facebook, MySpace, Flickr, Twitter, etc.<br/><br/>Flock is a great browser for online social networking, but falls a bit short compared to some of our higher ranked browsers in regards to features and utility.<br/><br/>Features Set:<br/>-While Flock does include most of the standard features like tabbed browsing, an integrated search engine, and a spell checker, it doesn't have parental controls, a smart toolbar, or at a glance security.<br/><br/>-Flock has plenty of tools built in to help you if you want to share photos, news, or simply your life story. Plus you can easily drag and drop to share videos, text, or favorite links.<br/><br/>-Ease of Use:<br/>Flock's slick interface is fairly intuitive and user-friendly. We had no problems navigating the Internet using Flock.<br/><br/>-Security:<br/>The Flock Internet browser is secure, with pop-ups, viruses, and spyware being blocked. You can also clear your browsing history quickly.<br/><br/>-Speed &amp; Compatibility:<br/>Though a little slower to load, Flock does a good job of keeping your web movement quick and easy. We had no issues with compatibility.<br/><br/>-Help/Support:<br/>Flock has provided several ways to get help if you need it. You can get support online, and through tutorials, FAQs, and user forums.<br/><br/>-Summary:<br/>Flock is an ideal browser for keeping you up to date with your online social contacts, but for other browsing you may wish to use one of our higher ranked internet browsers. You might consider using Flock as a secondary browser to keep in touch with friends, with Firefox or Google Chrome as your main browser.<br/><br/>&nbsp;<br/><br/><a href="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2010/10/flock2.png"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-400" title="flock." src="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2010/10/flock2.png?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="159" /></a><a href="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2010/10/flock-2.png"><img src="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2010/10/flock-2.png?w=300" alt="" title="flock-2" width="300" height="159" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-402" /></a>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Depression Detector]]></title>
    <link href="http://gotchacode.com/2010/08/depression-detector.html"/>
    <updated>2010-08-21T00:36:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gotchacode.com/2010/08/depression-detector</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="css-full-post-content js-full-post-content">
<strong><em>An online 'depression detector' developed in Israel can identify depression 78 percent of the time, according to a team of clinical psychologists</em></strong><br/><br/><strong><em><strong>A new algorithm developed by Israeli researchers can identify Internet users who are feeling depressed or suicidal.</strong></em></strong><br/><br/>You know that the Internet is a goldmine of information, but did you know that the Web is able to diagnose your emotional states and determine whether you are depressed, in love, feeling vengeful or aggressive? A new algorithm developed by Israeli researchers can pinpoint human emotions and intentions by studying vast amounts of publicly available data on blogs and other social media outlets.<br/><br/>Lead researcher Dr. Yair Neuman from Israel's Bar-Ilan University has especially promising results for identifying depression. The data provided by his application could help human experts to home in on who might be at risk for suicide. And the application, which skims the Internet automatically, can be adapted to any sort of data he says, presenting intriguing possibilities for crime fighters, pollsters or Homeland Security.<br/><br/>Currently enjoying a short summer sabbatical at the University of Toronto, Canada, Neuman will present his research in late August at the 2010 International Conference on Web Intelligence. He tells ISRAEL21c that he doesn't imagine that his invention will replace the human element, but rather that he views it as an aid to help sift through and make sense of the billions of bits of data about the human experience that are available online.<br/><br/>Neuman has used his application, which is funded by Israel's Defense Ministry, to scan more than 300,000 English language blogs linked to mental health websites. The software was programmed to identify the 100 most depressed, and the 100 least depressed individuals, by analyzing their responses to metaphors and questions.<br/><br/>The resulting data was handed over to a team of clinical psychologists, who confirmed a high correlation to what they would diagnose in the clinic, reporting that the software was able to identify depression 78 percent of the time.<br/><br/><strong>New software could pinpoint would-be terrorists</strong><br/><br/>"The software program was designed to find depressive content hidden in language that did not mention the obvious terms like 'depression or ‘suicide'," Neuman relates. "A psychologist knows how to spot various emotional states through intuition. Here, we have a program that does this methodically through the innovative use of 'Web intelligence'."<br/><br/>"I emphasize that the tool cannot substitute for an expert. It can provide a powerful way to screen for depression through blogs and Facebook. It analyzes text - the written language - and it can help us to identify people who are presenting signs of depression," he tells ISRAEL21c.<br/><br/>"Most who suffer from depression won't commit suicide. But this is a powerful way of screening for depression. It has psychosocial applications as well for Homeland Security - let's say monitoring depression levels of the population in a political circumstance to understand the population's sentiment."<br/><br/>The software can also "excavate" the meaning of context Neuman continues, testing for love, revenge and happiness among people, or even the way a society feels about its minorities. To date, the standard way to gain insight into these issues is through costly and time-consuming public opinion polls. The identification of people prone to vengeful behavior might also help to pinpoint would-be terrorists or criminals, he adds.<br/><br/>Another Israeli researcher, from the Hebrew University of Jerusalem, recently developed an <strong><a href="http://www.israel21c.org/201006108038/culture/a-tool-to-detect-sarcasm-online-yeah-right">online sarcasm detector</a></strong>, but Neuman says his approach is different: "I am analyzing the metaphor by sending queries to the web as questions, and understanding the way people metaphorically describe the answer.<br/><br/>"We could ask: What is love like? What is depression like? And look for how people describe the personal experience. We are harvesting a web of metaphors," he explains.<br/><br/><strong>Combining the wisdom of people with IT</strong><br/><br/>For now his tool won't be open source [meaning that for now the public does not have access to the end product's source material] and with no immediate plans for commercialization, Neuman isn't commenting on which, if any, agencies may be interested in the application. Still, his "no comment" suggests that it may be of interest to the US defense department. "It's not artificial intelligence, but intelligence augmentation, combining the wisdom of people with IT to mine a goldmine of data," he says.<br/><br/>The Mayo Clinic for example, offers a list of clues that someone may be suicidal and includes in its watch list "statements about hopelessness, helplessness or worthlessness, sudden changes in mood, direct or indirect statements that reference death or dying and isolating oneself from friends or family." These are signs loved ones can look out for, but what if the signs aren't obvious? This is where the Israeli application could help.<br/><br/>In the US alone, about 35,000 people commit suicide each year and the problem of diagnostics remains a challenge, since people identified as suicidal are those who are already seeking help, or those who have been 'diagnosed' through an online questionnaire. With increasing software advances, in the future diagnosticians will be able to scan the online world for more proactive signs of depression and suicide, for better intervention, monitoring and prevention.<br/><br/>While developed for academic purposes, the new Israeli findings could be used to screen for suicidal teens and bloggers, mining the Internet for the clues they may leave about their intentions, perhaps enabling friends and relatives to intervene in time, if someone they care about is at risk.
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Could Be Stylized by New W3c Font Platform]]></title>
    <link href="http://gotchacode.com/2010/08/web-could-be-stylized-by-new-w3c-font.html"/>
    <updated>2010-08-21T00:07:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gotchacode.com/2010/08/web-could-be-stylized-by-new-w3c-font</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="css-full-post-content js-full-post-content">
[caption id="attachment_137" align="alignleft" width="712" caption="Woff in IE9 "]<a href="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2010/08/1.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-137" title="1" src="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2010/08/1.jpg" alt="" width="712" height="480" /></a>[/caption]<br/><br/>While Web publishing continues to challenge the printed page as the primary means of sharing text, in one aspect it still lags behind <strong><em>Johannes Gutenberg's </em></strong>500 year old technology: Web developers have a relatively measly choice of fonts. Now the standards body for the Web is hoping to bring online the rich variety of type styles long availab <em>The World Wide Web Consortium's Web Fonts Working Group has launched version 1.0 of the The Web Open File Format (WOFF)</em>.<br/><br/>This format will provide a platform for open source and commercial providers of fonts to make their creations easily available across the Web, according to W3C fonts activity lead Chris Lilley.  "In print, publishers use lots and lots of fonts all the time. And there is a mechanism for that: They can get a font from a particular client, and use it on their computers," Lilley said. "And when designers come to the Web, they're in shock when they find they can't do that."<br/><br/>Today, the vast majority of text rendered on the Web is rendered by browsers in a small number of typefaces, most provided to the Web by Microsoft, such as Arial, Verdana and Times New Roman. (Typographically speaking, the term typeface refers to a stylistic rendition of each letter in an alphabet, whereas the font refers to the a specific rendering of these letters).  This collection is but a small subset of the wide range of typefaces available for print media, though. Various initiatives, most confined to specific browsers, have tried to expand the palette of fonts, but have failed to take off, due the amount of work they required on the part of Web developers.<br/><br/><strong> WOFF</strong> is an attempt to provide a platform for fonts that can be easily used by all browsers.  <strong>WOFF</strong> is actually a compression technology. A font owner can package a font in a<strong> WOFF</strong> container and post it on the Web. A browser, when it must render a page requiring the font, can download the font package, uncompress the font and use it to render the text. The page specifies the font needed with a Cascading Style Sheets(CSS)-based declaration.  The Mozilla Foundation provides an example page that allows the viewer to compare fonts already packaged in most browsers with a newly available<strong> WOFF</strong>-based downloadable font, the Charis SIL Compact (which is about a megabyte in size, or 80 kilobytes for the subset needed for the text). The Mozilla page allows the viewer to see how quickly the fonts load, as well as view the stylistic improvements. In the original incarnation, the page used a series of small images to render those letters that the browser could not render itself--the text itself is in the African Ewe and Adja languages. This technique of using images for letters slows the page loading time, gives the page an inconsistent lettering and makes the contents less scrutable to search engines....
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
