<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Apple | Gotchacode]]></title>
  <link href="http://gotchacode.com/blog/categories/apple/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gotchacode.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-26T13:15:55+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://gotchacode.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinit Kumar]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinitcool76@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What GNU/Linux Could Learn From Apple]]></title>
    <link href="http://gotchacode.com/2012/09/what-gnulinux-could-learn-from-apple.html"/>
    <updated>2012-09-02T08:01:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gotchacode.com/2012/09/what-gnulinux-could-learn-from-apple</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="css-full-post-content js-full-post-content">
<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on">A lot of recent posts on Hacker News suggest that Linux is dead on Desktop and OS X killed it. Well I don't think that it is still dead or it will be ever.<br />Instead of Lamenting on it, we should learn from our mistakes and also from success of OS X. Here are some of things we could do:<br /><br /><b>User Interface</b>: This is one place where OS X beats Linux by huge margin, Apple hire the best graphic designers and they put a lot of effort on how it looks and how&nbsp;intuitive is feels. Linux really need to improve on the UI specially we need excellent graphic designers that can create the next gen graphics. We could also take a lesson from Androids, they look awesome and they have a Linux at the core. The problem of fragmentation can be get rid with a unified great looking Desktop Environment that is functional as well as beautiful. We could always have the choice of other DE, but there should be one that could cater of masses of people who just want there OS to work and don't have the technical aptitude to tweak it.<br /><br /><b>Softwares</b>: This is one place where we have a lead. The only problem is that we don't have as much third party developers developing for Linux. One way to fix that is that we could have a central Software center that could provides softwares for almost all the Linux Distributions. Package management system could be merged into one or we could have a same package management in addition to the other package manager specific to that distro.<br /><br /><br /><b>Stability</b>: This is one thing that really needs to be addressed very seriously. No user wants his OS to crash performing an update or release upgrade. These issues should be addressed from the smallest level and only stable kernels should be included. Also advanced filesystem such as ZFS or BRFTS should be included as soon as possible such that we do fast backups and full system rollback.<br /><br /><b>Focus on Developers</b>: OS X earned a huge advantage because it focused on developers and provided everything they need on a very stable environment. We need to beat them in that. We have all the tools , we just need to make it more organized and less painful. Any new release should make it their first priority to see that setting a &nbsp;development environment is as easy as clicking a button on software center or by a unified command that fetches all dependencies. They could be grouped as say Rails Development, Python Development, PHP Development. Surely we can trim these unified packages if we need. But a developer not used to Linux would like to start with his development as soon as possible without learning to mess with the Operating system."<b><i>Just Works</i></b>" is a important factor that we need to focus on<i>.<b>It is very crucial because these are the developer who will build third party apps and availability of these apps could only attract masses to adopt Linux.</b></i><br /><i><b><br /></b></i>We need to play on our strengths rather than trying to imitate Apple. They have their limits, We have freedom to choose, We can offer our OS for free, They can't. We can give away open source softwares for free, They cant do that.With the other Hardware manufactures catching up soon, Apple won't have a next gen leap with their hardware. Android devices have already proved it is possible.<br /><i><b><br /></b></i><i style="font-weight: bold;">Imagine an OS with a UI better than Macs, and free softwares in vast Apt Repositories(just an example..don't kill me for it). Stability and full drivers support. This could be </i><b>Linux </b><b><i>that could really be the </i>Desktop of the Year.&nbsp;</b><br /><b><br /></b><b>P.S Everyone who hates these ideas are welcome to suggest better ones, i am just suggesting ideas and I am sure there are better ones.&nbsp;</b><br /><b><br /></b><b><br /></b><br /><br /></div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iPad 2 Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://gotchacode.com/2011/03/ipad-2-review.html"/>
    <updated>2011-03-04T10:35:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gotchacode.com/2011/03/ipad-2-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="css-full-post-content js-full-post-content">
<strong><strong><a title="iPad 2 : Thinner, Lighter and  Faster!  " href="http://gotchacode.wordpress.com/2011/03/04/ipad-2-launched/">iPad 2 : Thinner, Lighter and  <strong>Faster</strong>!</a></strong></strong><br/><br/>Amit Kr<br/><p style="text-align:justify;"><strong> </strong></p><br/><strong><a href="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/ipad_front_201103021.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-523 aligncenter" title="ipad_front_20110302" src="http://gotchacode.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/ipad_front_201103021.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="252" /></a></strong><br/><p style="text-align:center;">The new iPad2 ©</p><br/><strong>Now </strong>that the new iPad 2 has finally been announced; many of you might have been wondering if it is worth the efforts (read long queues) and the money to buy a new iPad 2. Well, I think the answer is a resounding Yes!! Apple has come with some innovative new features and great upgrades in iPad 2.  Here we preview some of the features of iPad 2 and also compare it with iPad so it is easy for our readers to decide if iPad 2 is worth the upgrade.<br/><br/>iPad 2 comes with a <strong>long list of features</strong>.  The first thing that got us excited in iPad 2 is the smart cover. There's a new cover for the device, which is best defined by Steve Jobs himself: "We designed the case right alongside the product. It's not a case -- it's a cover." Basically, it's a magnetic flap that protects the front and automatically wakes and puts the device to sleep according to whether it's open or closed. It takes only milliseconds to open and close the cover and the whole process is flawless.<br/><br/>The new iPad 2 is 15% lighter than iPad and at 613 grams , it feels very comfortable to hold in hands.  It is also 33% thinner than the original iPad and at just 8.8 mm, you really forget the device and get immersed in the Apple feeling.<br/><br/>You must have heard that external looks are not everything. It is what inside the heart that counts. Apple does not disappoint us at that too. With the new A5 Dual Core processor; the new iPad2 is claimed by Apple to be twice as fast and the graphics performance is up to nine times better than on the original iPad, while power requirements have been kept the same. Battery life is great with Apple promising 10 hours. That means you can keep yourself hooked to movies on that trans-Atlantic flight without worrying about recharge.<br/><br/>One of the great things about iPad 2 is the dual cameras : Front and rear cameras.  The front camera is a VGA camera that can be used for facetime chats with other iPad, iPhone, iPod, and Mac users.  The rear camera can shoot 720p HD video at 30 fps.<br/><br/>The new iPad will come with the newest version of Apple’s mobile operating system iOS 4.3.  This update enables better performance while using the Safari Internet browser, iTunes home sharing and Airplay improvements. It will also include the Wi-Fi hotspot capabilities found in the Verizon iPhones.<br/><br/>With built in gyroscope, high end processors and new apps for iMovie and GarageBand; the iPad 2 is a great multimedia experience.<br/><br/><strong>Pricing :</strong><br/><br/><strong>AT&amp;T introduced </strong><a href="http://www.att.com/gen/press-room?pid=19258&amp;cdvn=news&amp;newsarticleid=31658&amp;mapcode=broadband|consumer">two new postpaid plans for tablets</a>, a category that includes the <a href="http://www.tuaw.com/2011/03/02/apple-announces-ipad-2-in-2-colors-will-feature-dual-cameras-an/">upcoming iPad 2</a>. Unlike prepaid plans which require customers to buy data allotments upfront, these new plans can be added to a customer's current monthly cellular bill. This new postpaid option is month-to-month and does not require a long-term commitment.<br/><br/>Pricing for the postpaid plans mirror the prepaid plans with a $14.99 plan that provides 250 MB of data or a $25 plan with 2 GB of data. Overages on the new postpaid plans will be charged at a rate of $10 per 1 GB of overage. This is slightly less than the prepaid plans which charge customers $25 for an additional 2 GB of usage. These new plans give customers the freedom to choose how they would like to be billed for data to be used with their shiny new 3G iPad 2.<br/><br/>As a benefit for <a href="http://www.tuaw.com/2011/03/03/will-you-buy-an-ipad-2/">early adopters</a> of the iPad 2, AT&amp;T is offering a limited-time promotion that provides one free month of service for those that signup for the new $25/2 GB plan.<br/><br/>Below we have given a comparison table of iPad vs iPad 2.<br/><div><br/><table border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="5" width="475" align="center"><br/><tbody><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" align="center" valign="top"><strong>iPad</strong></td><br/><td width="170" align="center" valign="top"><strong>iPad 2</strong></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" align="center" valign="top"><img src="http://timenerdworld.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/ipadsm.jpg?w=488" alt="" /></td><br/><td width="170" align="center" valign="top"><img src="http://timenerdworld.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/ipad2sm.jpg?w=488" alt="" /></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Base Price</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top"><a href="http://store.apple.com/us/product/FB292LL/A?mco=MjEzNTI3MDQ">$349</a> (refurb), <a href="http://store.apple.com/us/product/MB292LL/A?mco=MjEzNzE1ODc">$399</a>(new)</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top"><a href="http://www.apple.com/ipad/">$499</a></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="170" valign="top"></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Colors</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top">Black</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top">Black or White</td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="170" valign="top"></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Dimensions</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top">9.56 x 7.47 x 0.5 inches</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top">9.5 x 7.31 x 0.34 inches</td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Weight</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top">1.5-1.6 pounds</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top">1.33-1.35 pounds</td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="170" valign="top"></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Storage</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top">16GB/32GB/64GB</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top">16GB/32GB/64GB</td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="170" valign="top"></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Connections</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top">Wi-Fi, Bluetooth, optional AT&amp;T 3G</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top">Wi-Fi, Bluetooth, optional AT&amp;T 3G or Verizon 3G</td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="170" valign="top"></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Screen</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top">9.7-inch 1024x768</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top">9.7-inch 1024x768</td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="170" valign="top"></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Processor</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top">1GHz A4</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top">1GHz dual-core A5</td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="170" valign="top"></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Battery</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top">Up to 10 hours</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top">Up to 10 hours</td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="170" valign="top"></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Cameras</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top">None</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top">720p rear, VGA front</td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="170" valign="top"></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Sensors</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top">Accelerometer, Ambient light sensor</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top">Accelerometer, Ambient light sensor, 3-axis gyro</td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top"></td><br/><td width="170" valign="top"></td><br/></tr><br/><tr><br/><td width="118" valign="top"><strong>Location</strong></td><br/><td width="186" valign="top">Wi-Fi, Compass, Optional GPS (3G version)</td><br/><td width="170" valign="top">Wi-Fi, Compass, Optional GPS (3G versions)</td><br/></tr><br/></tbody><br/></table><br/></div><br/><div><strong>Conclusion </strong>:</div><br/><div>With the great list of features and the magical Apple feeling found in every Apple device; I think iPad 2 is a great buy for new user and iPad users alike.  It will be available in stores and online from March 11.</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
