<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Life | Gotchacode]]></title>
  <link href="http://gotchacode.github.io/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gotchacode.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-14T17:28:36+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://gotchacode.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinit Kumar]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[vinitcool76@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Music, Movies and Life]]></title>
    <link href="http://gotchacode.github.io/2014/01/music-movies-and-life.html"/>
    <updated>2014-01-12T08:29:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gotchacode.github.io/2014/01/music-movies-and-life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="css-full-post-content js-full-post-content">
<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on">I love watching Movies and I love Music. They are almost inseperable part of life. I love the way they could touch and move your life more than you could imagine. I remember watching "The Social Network" almost 50 times in college. It served as a push to write more code and do awesome in life.<div><br /></div><div>Well, it might sound really strange but for last 10 years or so. I just let life flow in the natural way. I failed quite sometimes, achieved success as well. Made some long lasting friends, lost some people I felt who were my friends.</div><div><br /></div><div>The great thing is that in all these experiences, I realised that what is the true purpose of my life. They say, there are just two important days in your life.</div><div><br /></div><blockquote class="tr_bq">The day when you are born, and the day you find out why?</blockquote>I think I just found out the purpose of my life. It's not something I would want to disclose and claim I am going to achieve. It is the way my thinking changed and the choice of life I am going to make.<br /><br />Also, I would love to thank the wonderful readers of this blog - which initially started casually just to empty my mind on topics I felt were relevant at that time. For sure there are some not so good posts as well. But again, this blog is just me writing what comes in my mind. And if some of those helps someone or guide someone. Why not?<br /><br /></div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Is Information Overload and What to Do About It?]]></title>
    <link href="http://gotchacode.github.io/2013/11/what-is-information-overload-and-what.html"/>
    <updated>2013-11-30T18:13:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gotchacode.github.io/2013/11/what-is-information-overload-and-what</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="css-full-post-content js-full-post-content">
<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on">Each one of us uses one Social Network or another. It was fine in the earlier days when it was connecting you to your long lost friend, colleague or someone you knew. But do we realize what it is doing to us now?<br /><div><br /></div><div>We are being subjected to information overload and that too in the worst form. There are endless stories about all the stuff that doesn't even matter to us. We are being fed so much about our friends that we are not even interested to know about them anymore. Sharing every crap that happens in your life is a common norm and anyone who doesn't stick to it is dated.&nbsp;</div><div><br /></div><div>Well, that fact is, we should just shut this information overload and take control of our life. We don't really need to be subjected to this and become depressed and deprived people. Life has better meaning than all of it. We are born to do great things in life and not being sucked into this emotional and depressing wormhole that these Social Networks are creating.</div><div><br /></div><div>With that said, not all of the Social Networks are bad. Some of them like Twitter and Google+ gives us the option to minimise the intrusion of this excess information. So take a stand and control what kind of information gets to you. Clean up your friends and following list. Follow only those person and group you are really passionate &nbsp;about. Pick up some nice offline activity, meet some nice people , play some music, watch sunrise or sunset, start running etc. There are so many nice things to do. So just shut up laptop/tablets/smartphones and get some life people!</div></div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
